# Vishal Tien

Website | LinkedIn | GitHub | Email

#### SUMMARY

Passionate machine learning engineer with >2 years of experience in ML spanning both research and industry, specializing in natural language processing. Domain expertise in pharma / healthcare and looking to grow my skills in the tech industry

#### SKILLS

Technologies: PyTorch, HuggingFace, Scikit-learn, AWS, Flask, React, Spark, NoSQL, Neo4j, Docker

Programming Languages: Python, C++, R, MATLAB, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

## WORK EXPERIENCE

Roivant Sciences, New York, NY

July 2021 - Present

Tech Rotational Analyst

- Sumitovant, AI for Knowledge Discovery Team NLP Scientist
  - Developed tool that combines rule-based pattern matching and a fine-tuned T5 language model to assist researchers in retrieving relevant documents (i.e those mentioning drug side effects) from millions stored in NoSQL database
  - Tech lead for a knowledge graph based chatbot application powered by fine-tuning GPT-3 with hand-built Neo4j queries
- Sumitovant, Digital Innovator
  - Led the design and development of ML product that analyzes Sumitovant's corporate reputation using information extracted from the web, enabling recommendation of marketing actions to the VP of Communications in a Flask application
  - Built and deployed NLP deep learning models (i.e BART) using HuggingFace and AWS SageMaker for topic modeling and
    document classification trained with zero-shot learning approaches and human-in-the-loop techniques, enabling automation in
    a data scarce environment
  - Integrated ElasticSearch into backend to increase speed of information retrieval and developed an interactive d3.js frontend visualization for React application that streamlines manual processes in research scientist drug discovery workflow
- Sumitovant, AI for Knowledge Discovery Team Knowledge Graph / NLP Scientist
  - Built a biomedical knowledge graph (1M+ nodes and 4M+ edges) using Python and Turtle from disparate data sources to power a semantic search engine and enable previously unanswerable drug discovery questions to be addressed
  - · Implemented graph-based algorithms / GNNs to uncover insights from knowledge graph, such as disease-disease similarity
  - Trained a question answering information retrieval system by implementing an English to SPARQL (graph query language) deep learning generative language model, enabling the creation of a natural language interface that allows non-technical users to benefit form knowledge base, drastically increasing the impact it can have

# Tsui Lab at Children's Hospital of Philadelphia, Philadelphia, PA

AI Researcher

• Constructed a CNN-LSTM model in PyTorch that predicted presence of life-threatening cardiac condition from clinical patient data, ultimately improving performance of current state of the art hospital solution by 77%

## Merck & Co., Inc., Branchburg, NJ

Jun. 2020 – Aug. 2020

Dec. 2020 - July 2021

- Data Science Intern IT Emerging Talent Program
  - Built machine learning classification model with > 99% accuracy in Python to uncover relationships between large structured / unstructured datasets without data dictionaries, improving recall of previously best performing model by ~50%
  - Developed API wrapper written in R to allow data scientists to interact with a core product's API through easy-to-use functions

## **EDUCATION**

## University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA

August 2016 - May 2021

BSE in Bioengineering | Minors: Mathematics and Engineering Entrepreneurship (May 2020) | GPA: 3.8/4.0

MSE in Systems Engineering | Concentration in Data Science (May 2021) | GPA: 3.94/4.0

Awards: Senior Design Award, Rothberg Catalyzer Award, Publication, BMES Student Design and Research Award, Dean's List

#### **PROJECTS**

## An Evaluation of Abstractive and Extractive Deep Learning NLP Text Summarization Techniques

- Final project for Principles of Deep Learning graduate course required contributing to the deep learning research field Implementing Neural Network From Scratch
- Constructed neural network from scratch using pure python and numpy and compared performance to PyTorch network Predicting Inpatient Length of Stay at Hospitals (TowardsDataScience Blog Post)
- - Developed full-stack React / Node.js web application (<u>demo</u>) providing advanced restaurant search capabilities